Omar Qouqas

+1-365-656-0025 | +44-7400150025 | omar.qouqas@gmail.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/omarqouqas/ | https://github.com/omarqouqas | www.omaraiq.com

Immigration Status: Canadian Permanent Resident, relocating to Canada ASAP in 2020

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

An energetic IT professional with over 7 years of international experience ranging between Europe and the Middle East. I have an excellent track record of providing technical support in various industries, recently topped with an experience in software development.

Key skills include:

Core Java programming Customers service

Application support Maven SonarQube Git

MySQL Unix/Linux Commands

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Support Specialist

Jan 2018 - Present

GEANT • Cambridge, England

- · Creating monthly service reports via bash scripts and MySQL database queries
- Maintaining front-end GUI based on Java Server Pages
- Troubleshooting Java code, JSP pages and databases and making modifications as required
- Writing Java code to create new features
- Assisting in the collection and documentation of user requirements
- Recommending improvements to existing software programs as necessary
- Using Jira Kanban board to track issues
- Creating technical documentation for reference and reporting
- Triaging support tickets and coordinating with other team members

IT Support Engineer

Mar 2016 - Jan 2018

GEANT • Cambridge, England

- Creating new users, email accounts, security groups, distribution lists and joining machines to domain
- · Consulting technical manuals and other documents to research and implement solutions
- Writing technical specifications for purchase of PCs, networking hardware and related products
- Owning of desktop support tickets and related ticketing systems
- Day to day administration, operations, monitoring, troubleshooting and supporting of IT systems and desktop infrastructure

Service Desk Technician

Jun 2015 - Feb 2016

ITVET • Bishop's Stortford, England

Managing Windows domain controllers and Exchange Servers (i.e. setting up new users,

Omar Oougas 1 | Page

- email accounts, Security groups, Distribution lists, joining machines to domain)
- Building new PCs, Laptops and installing operating systems (Windows 7,8 and Windows 10) including hardware replacements (Memory, Hard Drives & Graphics Cards)
- Remote & on-site technical support including troubleshooting email profiles, configuring Outlook, mapping network drive, installing printers and scanners
- Installing Antivirus and creating Hosted Email Security policies via clients' control portal
- · Creating and managing group policies, login scripts and Users' home directories

Application Support Specialist

Feb 2014 - Apr 2015

Como • Ness Ziona, Israel

- Resolving technical issues escalated by the first line support team
- · Monitoring support queues and assigning tickets to team members
- Supporting various iOS and Android mobile apps and diagnosing bugs
- Delivering service and support to end-users remotely via a ticketing system

Technical Support Analyst

Mar 2012 - Oct 2013

AXSOS AG • Ramallah, Palestine

- First line desktop support for 500+ users in Germany, UK & Singapore.
- Working with customers and employees to identify computer problems and advising on the solution.
- Maintaining and administrating Active Directory, Domain Controllers, DHCP, DNS and user accounts.
- Logging and keeping records of users' queries.
- Creating Knowledge Base Articles for other team members.

Help Desk Analyst

Feb 2010 - Aug 2010

Al-Quds Network • Jerusalem, Palestine

- First point of contact for telephone and on-site support.
- Desktop support for our customers and staff (hardware and software), troubleshooting, administration and support of PCs, Laptops, Printers & other peripherals.
- · Documenting and updating daily support and maintenance reports.
- Performing repair, installation and support on staff machines.
- Liaising with Sales team to assist in packaging and pricing products (i.e. Laptops & PCs, Internet Services, Telecom Services)

EDUCATION

Master of Science, Cognitive Computing

Sep 2010 - Nov 2011

Goldsmiths, University of London • London, United Kingdom

Fully funded, Goldsmiths Humanitarian scholarship

Bachelor of Engineering (Hons), Computer Systems Engineer

Sep 2004 - Jun 2007

City, University of London • London, United Kingdom

Fully funded, Olive Tree scholarship

LANGUAGES

- Arabic Native language
- English Excellent working proficiency
- **Hebrew** Basic